Now I'll show you another design option for our panels.
I'll be using the same techniques of napkin decoupage with stickers to create a completely different design.
You'll need for this pretty napkin.
I'm using a daisy napkin with an all over design of flowers and grass.
I'm using a sticker book that I picked up in the store and the decoupage glue.
And you'll need some scissors for cutting.
Okay I'm going to use my daisy napkin here for the foreground and the base of a little fairy picnic.
So to use an all over design like this that I only want to have on the bottom here to kind of show that they're going to be sitting in the garden I want to cut my napkin.
But we don't want to cut straight across, we want to use the design in the napkin.
So what you do is cut out, as you go along, you cut out the flowers like this.
And then when you come to a grassy section instead of cutting straight across that grassy section you want to cut grass.
Okay, now I am going to just kind of cut straight here until I get down to another flower.
And then I am going to cut the grass.
And what you do is you just cut straight down in little diagonal snips like this.
And this will give the effect of that green turning into grass.
And do this all the way across the napkin as much space as you want.
Okay now when you have your foreground cut out.
You have your napkin cut you.
You see that we've turned an all over napkin into a nice piece of scenery.
And we're going to glue that down with the decoupage glue.
Okay you always want to check that you've got all the layers of the backing of the napkin.
And you take it down until you get a translucent, you can see it's a very thin piece of napkin.
Okay now to apply our napkin we're first going to take the decoupage glue and put a thin layer of the glue on the board.
You can use your hands for that.
You can also use a paint brush for putting down that first thin layer of glue.
When you're applying the napkin to the glue on the top then you want to use your finger or your hand so that you can feel how much pressure you're putting on the napkin.
The paint brush is a little bit too rough for that.
Okay and then once you have that thin layer of glue you want to very carefully place it down on the glue patting it into place.
And don't worry about a little bit of wrinkling.
That's normal with the napkin.
And it adds a little bit of texture and character to the design.
So just pat that down gently.
And then we'll glaze it over with some more of the decoupage glue.
Okay.
And when you're gluing you want to very, very gently make sure you have a lot of glue on your finger and it should be smooth and slick.
Now, I have the grass like this and the flower petals I want to glue in an upward motion.
You don't want to push it this way or you may tear your napkin.
And then just put a good layer all around on the napkin and look for air bubbles.
If you have air bubbles you want to put a little bit of glue there and kind of squish it out.
But very, very gently so you don't tear the napkin or get a hole in your design.